# ERVINS ZAGARS

# FRONT-END WEB <u>DEVELOPER</u>

**Email**: ervins.zagars@gmail.com **Portfolio**: <a href="https://ervinszagars.com/">https://ervinszagars.com/</a> **LinkedIn**: <a href="https://bit.ly/30DZL3R">https://bit.ly/30DZL3R</a>

A coder who is currently specializing in front-end development. Has also understanding of backend operations through building full MERN stack applications in a boot-camp setting.

Before worked in sales as a sales agent and later on as a team lead in the same company

# **HARD SKILLS:**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Git, Github, SCRUM

# **SOFT SKILLS:**

Team work, Task prioritization, Constructive feedback

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Revpanda Digital Agency 2020-currently**

#### Web Developer

- Building front-end for websites using HTML and CSS,
- Following professionally made designs on Adobe XD and Figma.
- Creating front-end functionality by using JavaScript and Jquery
- Optimizing FCP, LCP, and CLS scores to make sure website has a good SEO ranking.
- Recent work done for clients:
  - <a href="https://casinobee.com/">https://casinobee.com/</a>
- <a href="https://revpanda.com/">https://revpanda.com/</a>
- <a href="https://casinojinn.com/">https://casinojinn.com/</a>

### **International Travel Network 2017-2020**

#### Sales agent 2018-2019

- Tremendously improved communication skills by performing over the phone sales
- Got promoted to work with business class clients after nine months of being in the company

#### Sales Team Lead 2019-2020

- Took over an existing team consisting of individuals from many different countries and diverse backgrounds
- Improved interpersonal relationships within the team through team building activities
- Increased team generated revenue by 40%

# **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:**

# CryptoVisualizer (JS, React)

Code: <a href="https://bit.ly/2STZ3vb">https://bit.ly/2STZ3vb</a>

- Worked with two third party API's (cryptocompare.com.highcharts.com)
- Dynamically displayed information of user selected crypto currency on a graph.
- Used CSS Grid and styled-components library

# Linkedin Clone (MERN Full Stack App)

Code: <a href="https://bit.ly/3motHen">https://bit.ly/3motHen</a>

- Acquired understanding of full-stack development and how front-end, back-end are connected together
- Experience gained working in a team by following SCRUM principles
- Created REST API routes for user profiles using NodeJs

# Spotify Mockup (HTML, CSS)

Code: <a href="https://bit.ly/3nReDWt">https://bit.ly/3nReDWt</a>

- Created responsive design to fill all screen sizes
- Interface built using Bootstrap library

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Strive School 04.2020 - 10.2020

## **MERN STACK**

- MongoDB, ExpressJs, React, NodeJs
- Got also introduced to relational databases, specifically PostgreSQL

# **Swansea University 2014-2017**

#### **BS Criminology and Criminal Justice**

- Cybercrime: Deviance, Crime and Terror
- Terrorism and the Global Response
- Biological, Psychological and Social Crime Theories